<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Jellyfin: The Free Software Media System</title><link>https://jellyfin.org/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Jellyfin: The Free Software Media System</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://jellyfin.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New Android TV Release - v0.11.0</title><link>https://jellyfin.org/posts/android-tv-11/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jellyfin.org/posts/android-tv-11/</guid><description>&lt;p>Thank you for using Jellyfin! This is a major update for the Android TV client.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Jellyfin in 2019</title><link>https://jellyfin.org/posts/jellyfin-in-2019/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jellyfin.org/posts/jellyfin-in-2019/</guid><description>&lt;p>It feels hard to believe, but the Jellyfin project is now over a year old. With our official founding somewhere around December 8th 2018, Andrew and I weren't sure exactly what was going to happen. Did we have the resources to make a fork of Emby really happen? Were the doubters right in saying that we wouldn't last a year? It seems that we've proven them, and ourselves, wrong.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome to the New Website!</title><link>https://jellyfin.org/posts/welcome/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jellyfin.org/posts/welcome/</guid><description>&lt;p>Welcome to our brand new website.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At first glance, it may not look like much has changed - the theme and colours are still the same, and so is our frontpage. What has changed, is what's under the hood. Our website is now built using &lt;a href="https://www.gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a>, a static-page generator written in Go.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of the move, we've decided to introduce this new blog, where you'll be able to hear more about Jellyfin's new releases, future development, and goals. Occasionally, we'll feature guest posts from some of our own contributors.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>